Beyond Sherwood Forest is a action, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Peter DeLuise.
King Richard is away fighting the Crusade, his brother
Prince John has been left in charge.
In order to further international diplomatic relations with Norway, the
beautiful young Maid Marian is to be married off to a prince.
A cursed girl who can change into a ferocious dragon
is used to find and pacify Robin Hood.
Little John, played by Mark Gibbon.
Friar Tuck, played by Bill Dow.
Malcolm, played by Julian Sands.
Will Scarlet, played by Richard de Klerk.
Robin Hood, played by Robin Dunne.
Alina, played by Katharine Isabelle.
Sherwood Forest consists of the remnants of an ancient Royal Forest in
Nottinghamshire, in the East Midlands region of England.
It is associated with the legend of Robin Hood.
The forest was proclaimed by William the Conqueror and
mentioned in the Domesday Book in 1086.
The reserve has the highest concentration of ancient trees in Europe.
Today, Sherwood Forest National Nature Reserve encompasses 424.75 hectares (1,049.6
acres), surrounding the village of Edwinstowe and the site of Thoresby Hall.
The reserve contains more than a thousand ancient oaks which are known to be
more than 500 years old, with the Major Oak being twice that age.
Sherwood Forest is within an area which used to be called "Birch
Lund", which is Viking in origin, now known as Birklands.
The oak trees from Sherwood Forest were used to build the roof of St Paul's
Cathedral in London and 1st Viscount Nelson's naval fleet.
The film explores themes of robin hood, arrow, friar, arch, 12th century.